[WILLIAM] This class system
is a curse on civilization.
It causes people's hearts to
become poisoned and twisted.
As a result,
it gives rise to devils.
Therefore, the opposite
must also be true.
Once the demon is exorcised,
the heart can become pure.
And the curse, lifted.
Mark my words, this
country will be purified.
[WILLIAM] Are you going to
report me to Scotland yard?
As a nobleman,
I bet you'd like that--
to see me taken
away in shackles.
[ALBERT]
An orphan,
with the intellect to leave
even adults speechless.
Initially, I simply regarded
him as some sort of prodigy.
That was all.
Nothing else
triggered my interest.
But that soon changed.
Please come and live with me.
[SIMON]
Welcome home, Mister Albert.
Hold it right there.
[BOTH grunt]
You may be Mister
Albert's guests,
but I can't let you track
your filth into the foyer.
Go in through the back.
[ALBERT]
Simon!
Step back.
Those aren't just my guests
that you're insulting.
They're the newest
members of my family.
[SIMON grunts]
I don't understand.
What's the meaning of this?
I did tell you that we'd
be taking in an orphan.
[COUNTESS MORIARTY]
Yes, an orphan.
So why are there two of them?!
[EARL MORIARTY]
That was Albert's decision.
[COUNTESS MORIARTY] Well, why
don't you make him "decide"
which one he wants to keep?
[WILLIAM]
Shouldn't be a hard choice.
I hear the younger
one's quite ill.
We may as well be
adopting plague rats.
[COUNTESS MORIARTY] William has
the right of it, Darling.
What if these urchins get one
of our children sick?
[EARL MORIARTY]
This discussion is over.
The plague rats stay.
[DUCHESS PÉNIÈRES]
My goodness. Lord Moriarty.
I can't believe you've
adopted two orphans.
Well, I couldn't
just take in one.
They're brothers after all.
[EARL MORIARTY]
I've always felt it a duty
of those of us who have,
to extend a hand
to those who have not.
I hear that the younger
brother is quite ill,
but you're providing
for his treatment.
[EARL MORIARTY]
Indeed I am.
The doctor tells me the boy's
condition is quite serious.
The product of a lifetime
of hardships, no doubt.
That said, if all goes well
with the operation,
I'll make sure he
has a bright future.
[gasps] Oh!
[LOUIS groans]
[WILLIAM grunts]
[LOUIS groaning]
No, not again!
This is bad.
Just hold on,
I'll be back with help.
[LOUIS] No, wait, don't leave.
Please, just stay here.
I know how this
looks but I'm fine.
Trust me.
This'll be over before long.
I just need you with me.
That's all.
[WILLIAM]
You there!
I'm parched, why don't
you make me some tea?
Well, all right.
As you wish, Master William.
[LOUIS]
Is this all right?
No, it's not.
[LOUIS gasps]
[WILLIAM] We can muck
the grime from your skin
but not your mind, it seems.
What possessed you
to think I'd drink tea
made by a worthless
wretch like you?
What a mess you've made.
Albert didn't tell us you
weren't house-trained.
Come fix what you've done.
Clean it up with your tongue.
[WILLIAM]
Might I clean it in his place?
[LOUIS gasps]
[LOUIS]
Brother.
[chuckles] Trying to protect
your younger brother
from his own carelessness?
Familial love is
a beautiful thing.
I'm surprised that your kind
is capable of such a feeling.
Thought it would be
too complex for you.
However, if you truly wish
to be of help to your brother,
I should like you to teach him
that his actions
have consequences.
And naturally, since
you two are of a baser class,
you have a hard time learning
through conventional means.
So, drive the lesson
home with this.
Engrave it, lest he forgets.
[ALL gasping]
Does seeing this
make you feel better?
[ALBERT]
I'm sorry.
I wanted to offer you
a home, but not this.
We're in your debt
even now, my lord.
You've done nothing wrong,
so don't concern yourself
with our troubles.
You should go--your father
doesn't want you visiting.
I think he's afraid that
we'll taint you somehow.
I--
[WILLIAM]
Please, let it be.
What's wrong?
[LOUIS]
Nothing.
I guess I was just wondering.
Why do you think Mister Albert
invited us to live here?
Was it out of sympathy
for my illness?
Or a sense of aristocratic
obligation, maybe?
Despite his family, he's
been truly helpful to us.
But we're penniless orphans.
So I can't see how he expects
us to repay his kindness.
Or if he even does.
[WILLIAM] People use each
other without exception.
It's the principle
of mutual aid.
I don't consider it
such a bad thing.
He'll use us as we've used him.
After all, his offer
was quite generous.
For now, let's watch and wait.
He'll approach us soon.
And tell us what
he wants himself.
Though if this
were a horse race,
I'd be ready to
place my bet now.
[COUNTESS MORIARTY]
William.
You're due to attend
classes at Eton College
before too long, aren't you?
I do wish you'd commit
to your studies more.
I would, but I
can't concentrate.
Not while you're raising
those low-born parasites
under our roof.
There's no telling
what they might do
if I lower my guard around them.
Well? What do you think?
Can we end this farce yet?
Frankly, we should've run
those two off a while ago.
We cured the younger
one's illness, haven't we?
That's enough to
save appearances.
That doesn't even come close.
If we dismiss them,
the gossip will be insufferable.
And I'll be the one who has
to suffer the brunt of it.
If only one of them
would commit some sort of crime.
Then we could be rid
of them without a fuss.
[EARL MORIARTY]
Incidentally, William.
As I was boarding my
carriage in town yesterday,
some street peddler
offered me his thanks.
He made it sound like you'd done
some sort of favour for him.
Well, that's odd.
He must've had the wrong person.
You would never
catch me wasting my time
talking to a street peddler.
Honestly, they're only
a half-step up from beggars.
They certainly have the same
smell of sweat and piss.
Well, you can't argue with that.
Don't encourage him
to say such filth.
At least not during
our meals. It's unseemly.
[WILLIAM]
Fine, forget the urchins.
Oh! My birthday will be the
same day as Easter this year,
so my party needs
to be larger than usual.
Can I invite anyone?
[EARL MORIARTY]
None of the children
from Baron Kimble's family.
I'm told that they've run into
financial trouble as of late.
[WILLIAM]
Right.
He's just a life peer anyway,
so they won't inherit.
[COUNTESS MORIARTY]
Be sure that the son of the
Marquess of Lytton attends.
[clattering]
[BOTH grunt]
Is everything all right
with you, Albert?
You've been acting rather
strange as of late.
[ALBERT]
You're the ones who are strange.
[COUNTESS MORIARTY gasps]
Wait, Albert!
Come back!
[ALBERT]
I don't want to talk to you.
Or hear your voices.
Or look at your faces.
All that power.
All that privilege.
And you wield it only
to push others down.
You're befouling this world.
And I can't stop you.
[ALBERT] The world as
I know it is driven by "status."
Everyone covets it.
Hoards what they can.
And feign like they have more.
It makes us look up
at some in envy
and down at the rest in scorn.
[ALBERT] Why is this
family--this world
so horrifically cruel?
So twisted?
[ALBERT]
Do you have the answer?
These people are poison.
They taint the very
air they breathe.
Am I wrong?
I don't think so.
Is this how you'd like me to
make good on my debt to you?
[EARL MORIARTY snores]
[WILLIAM chuckles]
[WILLIAM]
How convenient.
[gasps]
Wait! I thought I saw
you asleep in your bed.
[gasps]
[WILLIAM]
This is perfect.
You've saved me the trouble of
having to move your body later.
Hold on. What are
you talking about?
[WILLIAM]
I see now.
You thought you'd hide
that silverware in our room
and then "discover it" later.
That way you could frame us as
thieves and have us thrown out.
I've heard worse plans.
[grunts]
[yelps]
[WILLIAM] Wait. Just what
are you planning to do?
Murder me?
No. There's someone else
who wants to deal with you.
Huh?
[WILLIAM]
Brother?
You wouldn't.
[ALBERT]
Am I wrong
to want to kill for my ideals?
I don't think so.
Is this how you'd like me to
make good on my debt to you?
[ALBERT]
Yes, it is. I need your help.
Give me the wisdom and courage
to achieve my ambitions.
Wisdom I can give.
I'm a consultant
of sorts, after all.
That said, you shouldn't
look to me for courage.
[WILLIAM]
Look to yourself.
Albert, please.
How can you even consider this?
Nice to see that you'd
strike first if you could.
[gasps, chuckles] Oh, please.
What damage could
a little fork do?
I would never
hurt you; we're family.
Come on. We share
the same blood. So--
[ALBERT]
Shut your mouth.
The mere idea
the same tainted blood
flows through both of our veins
is enough to make
me want to vomit.
I hold you,
this family,
this whole society in contempt!
I've resolved to change it.
And that starts tonight.
The world I make
will have no place
for people like you.
- -So, die.
- -[WILLIAM groans]
[WILLIAM groans, whimpers]
[panting]
[WILLIAM]
Thank you, Albert.
You've demonstrated
the strength of your resolve.
[WILLIAM]
If you pull that out now,
you'll die of rapid blood loss.
It's not essential, but
I'd prefer it if you drew
breath a while longer.
In the unlikely event of
a coroner's inquest
on your corpse,
I'd prefer what's left of your
lungs to have internal burns
from inhalation
of searing hot smoke.
[gasps] You... can't.
[WILLIAM]
Hm.
Come. We need to
finish what we've started,
quickly.
[WILLIAM]
In the wake of it all,
we want the thought of foul play
to be far from
any onlooker's minds.
If we make this look
like a tragic accident,
we can prevent an investigation.
[WILLIAM]
This is the blueprint
of what you'd call
a perfect crime.
One sure-fire way
to dispose of evidence
is to burn your
crime scene to ash.
Normally, it would be quite
the challenge to burn down
an entire manor of this size.
We'll do it by causing
a major gas leak.
Gas lighting is exceedingly
common these days.
Naturally, we get
the occasional leak.
And the occasional fire.
Thus, there's an extremely
high probability that this
will be considered nothing
more than a tragic accident.
This cellar should
be relatively airtight.
So, we'll be safe from
the initial blast at least.
[WILLIAM] There's nothing
left to do now but wait.
The manor's filling
with gas as we speak.
[gasping]
[ALBERT grunts]
Let's go. It's coming down.
[LOUIS grunts]
What're you doing?
[groans]
Louis, don't!
Why would you do that?
'Cause it maximizes our chances.
And with all our
futures at stake,
it's a small price to pay.
Had we come out
of this unscathed,
someone might've doubted us.
But this wound makes it
clear that we barely escaped.
Also, I still owe you two
for saving me from my illness.
[WILLIAM gasps]
[LOUIS] Please accept this
as my way of repaying you.
And as proof of my resolve
to stand beside you,
engraved, lest I forget.
[ALBERT] As comrades,
accomplices, and family--
this is how we're going to live.
[WILLIAM]
Once the demon is exorcised,
the heart can become pure.
And the curse, lifted.
Mark my words, this
country will be purified.
Please come and live with me.
[gasps]
[ALBERT] I wish to
combine my noble status
with your brilliant mind.
With my wealth, my privilege,
and my loyalty
you shall have all the tools you
need to realize your ambitions.
Use them as you please
and show me the world
as you wish it to be.
Look! There are survivors!
Doctor! Quickly!
[FIREMAN 2A]
Are you all right?
My name is Albert.
Albert James Moriarty.
[ALBERT]
And these two are my brothers,
William and Louis.
[WILLIAM] After the fire,
we were the last of our family.
Lacking anyone else to turn to,
the three of us
relied on each other
and strove to push forward.
That sounds absolutely dreadful.
I'm so sorry for dredging up
such unpleasant memories.
That said, it sounds like
you got to grow up in
a truly warm household.
A stately father,
a loving mother,
and a quartet of loyal brothers.
It's tragic that you
were torn apart.
But for a time at least,
you had the perfect family.
Yes.
[WILLIAM]
Quite.
[WILLIAM] Next time
on Moriarty the Patriot  .
"A Rare Breed."